this is a day I've been looking forward
to for two and a half years every once
in a while a revolutionary product comes
along that changes everything
and Apple has been well first of all
ones very fortunate if you get to work
on just one of these in your career
apples been very fortunate it's been
able to introduce a few of these into
the world 1984 we introduced the
Macintosh it didn't just change Apple it
changed the whole computer industry
in 2001 we introduced the first iPod and
it didn't just it didn't just change the
way we all listen to music it changed
the entire music industry well today
we're introducing three revolutionary
products of this class the first one is
a widescreen iPod with touch controls
the second is a revolutionary mobile
and the third is a breakthrough internet
communications device so three things a
widescreen iPod with touch controls a
revolutionary mobile phone and a
breakthrough internet communications
device an iPod a phone and an Internet
communicator an iPod a phone
these are not three separate devices
this is one device
and we are calling it iPhone
today
today Apple is going to reinvent the
phone and here it is
No
actually here it is but we're gonna
leave it there for now so before we get
into it
let me let me talk about a category of
things the most advanced phones are
called smart phones so they say and they
typically combine a phone plus some
email capability plus they say it's the
internet or the baby internet into one
device and they all have these plastic
little keyboards on them and the problem
is that they're not so smart and they're
not so easy to use so if you kind of
make a you know business school 101
graph with a smart axis and the easy to
use axis follows regular cell phones are
kind of right there they're not so smart
and they're you know not so easy to use
but smart phones are definitely a little
smarter but they actually are harder to
use they're really complicated just for
the basic stuff people have a hard time
figuring out how to use them well we
don't want to do either one of these
things what we want to do is make a
leapfrog product that is way smarter
than any mobile device has ever been and
super easy to use this is what iPhone is
okay we're gonna reinvent the phone now
we're gonna start with a revolutionary
user interface is the result of years of
research and development and of course
it's an interplay of hardware and
software now why do we need a
revolutionary user interface I mean
here's four smartphones right Motorola
cue the BlackBerry Palm Treo nokia e62
the usual suspects and what's wrong with
their user interfaces well the problem
with them is really sort of in the
bottom 40 they're it's it's this stuff
right here they all have these keyboards
that are there whether you need them or
not to be there and they all have these
control buttons that are fixed in
plastic and are the same for every
application well every application wants
a slightly different user interface a
slightly optimized set of buttons just
for it and what happens if you think of
a great idea six months from now you
can't run around and add a button to
these things they're already shipped so
what do you do it doesn't work because
the buttons and the controls can't
change they can't change for each
application and they can't change down
the road if you think of another great
idea you want to add to this product
well how do you solve this hmm
it turns out we have solved it we solved
it in computers 20 years ago we solved
it with a bitmap screen that could
display anything we want put any user
interface up and a pointing device we
solved it with the mouse right we solve
this problem so how are we gonna take
this to a mobile device but what we're
gonna do is get rid of all these buttons
and just make a giant screen a giant
screen now how are we gonna communicate
this we don't want to carry around a
mouse right so what are we gonna do
Oh a stylus right we're gonna use a
stylus No
who wants a stylus you have to get them
and put them away and you'll lose them
yuck
nobody wants a stylus so let's not use a
stylus we're going to use the best
pointing device in the world we're gonna
use a pointing device that we're all
born with were born with ten of them
we're gonna use our fingers we're going
to touch us with our fingers and we have
invented a new technology called
multi-touch which is phenomenal it works
like magic you don't need a stylus it's
far more accurate than any touch display
that's ever been shipped it ignores
unintended touches it's super smart you
can do multi-finger gestures on it and
boy have we patented it
so we've been very lucky to have brought
a few revolutionary user interfaces to
the market in our time
first was the mouse the second was the
click wheel and now we're gonna bring
multi-touch to the market and each of
these revolutionary user interfaces has
made possible a revolutionary product
the Mac the iPod and now the iPhone so a
revolutionary user interface we're gonna
build on top of that with software now
software on mobile phones is like it's
like baby software it's not so powerful
and today we're gonna show you a
software or breakthrough software that's
at least five years ahead of what's on
any other phone now how do we do this
well we start with a strong foundation
iPhone runs OS 10
why
why would we want to run such a
sophisticated operating system on a
mobile device well because it's got
everything we need
it's got multitasking it's got the best
networking it already knows how to power
manage we've been doing this on mobile
computers for years it's got awesome
security and the right apps it's got
everything from cocoa and the graphics
and it's got core animation built in and
it's got the audio and video that OS 10
is famous for it's God all the stuff we
want and it's built right in to iPhone
and that has led us create desktop class
applications and networking right not
the crippled stuff that you find on most
phones this is real desktop class
applications now you know one of the
pioneers of our industry Alan Kay has
had a lot of great quotes throughout the
years and I ran across one of them
recently that explains how we look at
this explains why we go about doing
things the way we do because we love
software and here's the quote people who
are really serious about software should
make their own hardware you know Alan
said this thirty years ago
and this is how we feel about it and so
we're bringing breakthrough software to
a mobile device for the first time it's
five years ahead of anything on any
other phone the second thing we're doing
is we're learning from the iPod syncing
with iTunes you know we're gonna ship
our hundred millionth iPod this year and
that's a tens of millions of people that
know how to sync these devices with
their PCs or Mac and sync all of their
media right onto their iPod right so you
just drop your iPod in and it
automatically syncs you're gonna do the
same thing with iPhone it automatically
syncs to your PC or Mac right through
iTunes and iTunes is going to sync all
your media onto your iPhone your music
your audio books podcasts movies TV
shows music videos but it also syncs a
ton of data your contacts your calendars
photos which you can get on your iPod
today your notes your your bookmarks
from your web browser your email
accounts your whole email setup all that
stuff can be moved over to iPhone
completely automatically it's really
nice and we do it we do it through
iTunes again you go to iTunes and you
set it up just like you'd set up an iPod
or an Apple TV and you set up what you
want sync to your iPhone and it's just
like an iPod charge and sync
so sync with iTunes third thing I want
to talk about a little is design we've
designed something wonderful for your
hand just wonderful and this is what it
looks like it's got a three-and-a-half
inch screen on it it's really big and
it's the highest resolution screen we've
ever shipped it's a hundred and sixty
pixels per inch
highest we've ever shipped it's gorgeous
and on the front there's only one button
down there we call it the home button it
takes you home from wherever you are and
that's it
let's take a look aside it's really thin
it's thinner than any smartphone out
there at eleven point six millimeters
thinner than the Q thinner than the
Black Jack thinner than all of them it's
really nice and we got some controls on
the side we got a little switch for ring
and silent we've got a volume up and
down control let's look at the back on
the back the biggest thing of note is we
got a two megapixel camera built right
in the other side and we're back on the
front so let's take a look at the top
now we've got a headset jack
three-and-a-half millimeter all your
iPod headphones fit right in we've got a
place a little tray for your SIM card
and we've got one switch for sleeping
wake just push it to go to sleep push it
to wake up let's take a look at the
bottom we've got a speaker you've got a
microphone and we've got our 30 pin iPod
connector so that's the bottom now we've
also got some stuff you can't see we've
got three really advanced sensors
built into this phone the first one is a
proximity sensor it senses when physical
objects get close so when you bring
iPhone up to your ear to take a phone
call it turns off the display and it
turns off the touch sensor instantly why
do you want to do that well one to save
battery but - so you don't get spurious
inputs from your face into the touch
screen just automatically turns them off
take it away boom it's back on so it's
got a proximity sensor built in it's got
an ambient light sensor as well we sense
the ambient lighting conditions and
adjust the brightness of the display to
match the ambient lighting conditions
again better user experience saves power
and the third thing we've got is an
accelerometer so that we can tell when
you switch from portrait to landscape
it's pretty cool you show it to you in a
minute
so three advanced sensors built-in so
let's go ahead and turn it on this is
the size of it it fits beautifully in
the palm of your hand so an iPod phone
and an Internet communicator let's start
with the iPod you can touch your music
you can just touch your music it's so
cool you got a widescreen video you can
find your music even faster
gorgeous album art on this display
built-in speaker and why not cover flow
first time ever on an iPod and so rather
than talk about this some more let me
show it to you
all righty now I've got some special
special iPhones up here they've got a
little special board in them enough so I
can get some digital video out I got a
little cord here which goes up to these
projectors and so I got some great
images and you get to see what it really
looks like
so let me I've got a camera here so you
can see what I'm doing with my finger
for a few seconds and let me go ahead
and get that picture within picture up
I'm going to go ahead and just push the
sleep/wake button there we go right
there and to unlock the phone I just
take my finger and slide it across all
right I'm gonna see that again
they sleep we wanted something that you
couldn't do by accident in your pocket
and just slide it across boom and this
is the home screen of iPhone right here
and so if I want to get in the iPod I
just go down that lower right-hand
corner and push this icon right here and
boom I'm in the iPod I want to get home
I push the home button right here and
I'm home back in the iPod I'm back in
the iPod now here I am you see five
buttons across the bottom playlists
artists songs videos and more I'm an
artist right now well how do i scroll
through my list of artists how do I do
this I just take my finger and I scroll
I mean that cool little rubber banding
up when I run off the edge and if I want
to pick somebody let's say I want to
pick the Beatles I just tap them and
here's the Beatles songs with their
albums right here
want to play Sgt pepper's I just hit Sgt
pepper's right there and you know it'll
help for my friends look at this
gorgeous album artwork here of course I
got a blow in control now I've got a
little button up in the corner right
here you can see in the upper right hand
corner I can hit that and flip the album
art around there's all the other songs
back here and I can play lovely Rita if
I want to flip it back around
very simple alright I can set some stars
back here just by setting the arrows
that's a 5 stuff yeah
let me show you something else I just
take my unit here and I turn it
landscape mode oh look what happens I'm
in cover flow what's going to Dylan here
let's play like a rolling stone
I just come through
come through my albums real easy any
time I find something I like I'm just
turned around play something that easy
it's that simple
and that great yeah
all right I could play with this for a
long time now again I've got playlists
here I can go into my playlists I've got
artists I've got songs I've got more
over here I've got you know albums I got
a great album view again that shows all
my album artwork right here if I want
and I've also got audiobooks and
compilations since things like that I've
also got videos here so I push videos
and I've got here I've got a pod cavity
of podcasts loaded on in a music video
and I've got TV show in a movie and I'd
like to just show you the TV show here
this is an episode from the office all
videos we look at in Atlanta NBC
presentation
who are you faxing so early in the
morning Oh Ana who explained I don't
have a ton of contact with his grand
branch but before I left I took a box of
Dwight's stationery so from time to time
I send Dwight faxes from himself from
the future
Dwight at 8 a.m. today someone poisons
to coffee do not drink the coffee
more instructions will follow cordially
future Dwight
we have touch controls on here of course
and that awesome awesome let's go and I
want to show you a movie playing let's
play Pirates of the Caribbean the second
one here great movie by the way and now
this is a widescreen movie so I just
DoubleTap and I can see the whole thing
here all right off the screen whichever
I like
and again I've got on-screen controls
here it's cool so we can be watching
future length movies just like this
alrighty so that is the iPod pretty cool
huh
we've just started so again touch your
music just scroll through your songs
scroll through your playlist that's
incredible widescreen video like you've
never seen on a portable device 160
pixels per inch gorgeous screen quality
gorgeous album art and Cover Flow it's
the best ipod we've ever made
again some of the screenshots it's
unbelievable here's some album art I
just put up so you see what it looks
like just no matter what you like it
looks pretty doggone gorgeous
and of course coverflow and video with
on-screen controls
you know I was showing this to somebody
I was giving a demo to somebody a little
while ago who had never seen this before
inside Apple and I finished the demo I
said what do you think he told me this
he said you had me at school so the
iPhone with the most amazing iPod ever
you can now touch your music so that's
the iPod now let's take a look at a
revolutionary phone we want to reinvent
the phone now what's the killer app the
killer app is making calls it's amazing
it's amazing how hard it is to make
calls on most phones most people
actually dial them every time most
people don't have very many numbers in
their address book they use their
recents as their address book right how
many of you do that I bet more than a
few so we want to let you use contacts
like never before you can sync your
iPhone with your PC or Mac and bring
down all your contacts right into your
phone so you've got everybody's numbers
with you at all times we have something
that's going to revolutionize voicemail
today we call it visual voicemail
wouldn't it be great if you didn't if
you had six voicemails if you didn't
have to listen to five of them first
before you wanted to listen to the sixth
will not be great if you have
random-access voicemail well we've got
it just like email you can go directly
to the voicemails that interest you
excellent all of the audio quality
iPhone is a quad-band GSM + H phone we
have decided
we've decided to go with the most
popular international standard which is
GSM we're on that bandwagon headed on
that roadmap and plan to make 3G phones
and all sorts of other amazing things in
the future so quad bad gsm plus h and of
course we have Wi-Fi and bluetooth 2.0
EDR built-in as well and so this is what
it looks like when you get a call this
is what it sounds like it's one of our
ringtones you can pick of course so I
want to show you four things I want to
show you the phone app photos got a
calendar and SMS messaging the kind of
things you would find on a typical phone
but in a very untypical way now so let's
go ahead take a look so let's go to our
phone first you see that icon in the
lower left-hand corner the phone I just
push it right here and boom I'm in the
phone and I've got five buttons across
the bottom favorites recents contacts
keypad and voicemail I'm in contacts
right now again how do I move around my
contacts I just scroll through them and
so let's say I want to make a call to
Johnny I've I can just push here and I
see Johnny Ives context with all his
information his three phone numbers his
email whatever else is address whatever
else I've got it's all in one place and
if I want to call Johnny all I do is
push his phone number I'll call his
mobile number right now and now we are
calling Johnny here it turned on a
speaker phone like this if I wanted to
hey Johnny how you doing well it's been
two and a half years and I can't tell
you how thrilled I am to make the first
public phone call with iPhone
I I remember when we first started
working on this and it's just it's just
unbelievable whoa whoa what is this I've
got another call coming in Johnny can I
put you on hold for a minute okay so I
put Johnny on hold and hi Phil all right
Phil as you can see it's put it's put
Johnny on hold and feel I can just touch
Johnny and bring Johnny back hey Johnny
you there hey listen Phil called did you
mind if I conference them in you can see
the button has changed to merge calls
right there in the middle so I just push
that right here and now I've created a
conference call
johnny you there yeah Phil you there oh
so here we are and now listen I got to
get back to my key notes so if I want to
do that what I mean I just touch this
arrow right here and I'm gonna go ahead
and take Johnny private here and put
Phil on hold Johnny do you have anything
to say on the first phone call it's not
too shabby
you take care of Johnny and I end this
call and it fills on hold I take him off
a hold Phil thanks very much I got to
get back to the keynote now bye-bye
all righty
so
now I've also got a way to make a list
of favorites here from my most often
called numbers so I can just touch it
once and dial dial the number and I
might want to add somebody to favor it
so let's say I want to add Phil Schiller
I just push that plus button in the
upper right hand corner right there and
I'll pop my favorites and I can just go
to the s is here and there's Phil so
Phil Schiller right there and I'll put
let's say I want to put Phil's work
number and it's added Phil right there
you can see the favorites I can edit
favorites by pushing the edit button in
the upper left-hand corner and I can
move Phil up if I want to you know maybe
the top and let's say I'm not gonna you
know type Tony's changed his number I
got to update this anyway so I'm gonna
get rid of that and I could just remove
Tony boom there we go it's that simple
to edit these things very very easy
I've got recents right here which is all
my recent phone calls if I want to see
the ones I've missed which you're in red
I can just go up and touch that button
at the top and boom those are all the
ones I've missed and those are all the
calls that I've placed or have done if I
want to dial the phone if I'm real last
century
I can push keypad here and I can dial a
call just with oops called for sorry
wrong number
4:08 16 and it formats the numbers and
if I want to I can just keep dialing
let's say it's a European number and the
numbers just keep getting smaller real
simple very simple to that with a keypad
now let me show you visual voicemail
this is so cool this is a collaboration
that we've done which I'll talk more
about later and it allows us to have
random access voicemail go directly to
the voicemails we want so as an example
I come to my voicemail I know there's
one by Al Gore I want to hear that one I
just push it I'm here in Nashville
training people to give my slide show
but I wanted to say congratulations on
the iPhone it is unbelievably cool good
luck with the presentation call me later
now if I want to call al back right now
I can just push that callback button
but I want to listen to one from Tim
Cook I got here so let me listen to Tim
Davis Tim I've got the results for last
quarter revenue was if you know I'll
just wait and tell you what you get it
first and as awesome and so I've got
voicemail how I want to listen to it
when I want to listen to it in any order
I want to listen to it with visual
voicemail so that is a quick tour of the
phone app now what I want to do is show
you SMS texting so I just go to that SMS
icon in the upper left hand corner and
push it and I not only have SMS texting
but I have multiple sessions so I can be
carrying on conversations with people
and every time I get a new message from
them I'll be alerted to that and I can
go check it out so as an example here
I've got Eddy Cue and I've been carrying
on a conversation with Eddie and I just
tap this and here's the conversation
I've been carrying on right here right
and if there's a new message look at me
so there's a new message from Phil and
let's see the conversation was what hey
Steve hi
still on for dinner tonight absolutely
your turn to pick I've picked sushi Ron
how about seven o'clock tonight and I
said I can just say you know sounds
great I've got this little keyboard
which is phenomenal it does air for
prevention and correction and not that I
wouldn't make some I probably will but
it's actually really fast the type on
it's faster than all these little
plastic keyboards and all these smart
phones so I can just say sounds great
see you there
and I can send that and there it is
and when Phil messages me back I'll be
alerted I'll see the dot and I can just
go pick up that conversation where it
left off if I want to send a message to
Eddie I or Scott I just push this and
send a message and go it's so simple
so that's SMS messaging and you know I
again you've seen the keyboard it's
pretty awesome we'll come back to that a
little bit later and the third app I
want to show you as part of the phone
package is photos you know we have a two
megapixel camera built-in as I said we
also have the coolest photo management
app ever certainly on a mobile device
but I think maybe ever
and so here's here's our photos I'm
gonna go into our photo library and this
is our library and again I can just
scroll through photos here with my
finger pretty cool let me go to a photo
album I'll pick Italy and I just let's
start at the top and to go through
pictures I just swipe them just swipe
through my photo library oh there's one
that's this landscape I can just turn my
device and take a look at it
pretty cool huh right so I can even
swipe when I'm in landscape here you
know missile awesome the other thing I
can do is I can take any of these
pictures and I can make them bigger and
so let me go ahead and get the camera
back up yeah there it is right there
I can I can just take my fingers and I
can we call it the pinch I can bring
them closer together and move them
further apart to make it bigger or
smaller and so I can just move them
further apart and stretch the image
and move it around
and now
now what I can do is I can pick to what
make this Maya wallpaper and of course I
could you know jigger it around then and
just set the wallpaper and now when I if
I'm back at home and I go to sleep when
I wake up from here on out until I reset
it
that's my wallpaper whenever I'm making
a call that's what I'm gonna see boom
there we go so photos SMS and the phone
app that is part of our phone package
for iPhone
get a call again really great color
management features just scroll through
contacts with your finger all the
information at your fingertips here
favorites last century visual voicemail
calendar SMS texting incredible photo
app the ability to just take any picture
and make it your wallpaper it's pretty
unbelievable and I think when you have a
chance to get your hand on it you'll
agree we have reinvented the phone okay
so now let's take a look at an internet
communications device it's part of
iPhone so what's this all about well
we've got some real breakthroughs here
start off with we've got rich HTML email
on iPhone the first time really rich
email on a mobile device and it works
with any IMAP or pop email service you
got your favorite mail service it'll
likely work with it and it's rich text
email we wanted the best web browser in
the world on our phone not a baby web
browser or a WAP browser a real web
browser and we picked the best one in
the world Safari and we have Safari
running on iPhone it is the first fully
usable HTML browser on a phone third
we have Google Maps Maps satellite
images directions and traffic this is
unbelievable wait till you see it we
have widgets starting off with weather
and stocks and this communicates with
the internet over edge and Wi-Fi and
iPhone automatically the text Wi-Fi and
switches seamlessly to it you don't have
to manage the network it just does the
right thing now I want to take a second
to talk about email we hook up to almost
any IMAP or pop 3 mail service I just
want to give you some examples
IMAP of course is the best because you
can keep your folders and all your email
on the server and access it from
anywhere Yahoo Yahoo Mail is IMAP
Microsoft Exchange has an IMAP option
and obviously dot Mac mail is IMAP as
well
pop3 Google Gmail AOL Mail and most ISPs
are pop3 email now I want to take a
minute and highlight one yahoo mail
yahoo mail is the biggest mail service
in the world they have over a quarter
billion users biggest email service in
the world and today we are announcing
with yahoo that they are going to
provide free push IMAP email to all
iPhone customers so this isn't just IMAP
email it is push IMAP email so when you
get a message it'll push it right out to
the phone for you same as a blackberry
free IMAP push email from Yahoo so we
think this is a pretty big deal so what
I'd like to do now is I'd like to show
you mail Safari Google Maps and widgets
running on iPhone so let's go see
so let's go into male second icon from
the left on the bottom there I just
touch it with my finger and boom I'm
there and so I've got an inbox here and
this is by the way running live on Yahoo
IMAP email this stuff is coming off of
Yahoo's servers somewhere up in the
cloud
and so I say James Vincent here sent me
an email
he's a proud father and there we go and
I can just scroll here I've got inline
photos rich text email there we go let's
look at another one Phil Schiller she
loved the gift again inline photos rich
text pretty nice shopping list again
rich text right here pretty cool
directions to sushi Ron for tonight's
dinner now iPhone of course parses out
phone numbers and as you can see there's
a phone number in blue I can just touch
it and boom I'm gonna call this place
alright I don't really want to call him
so I'm gonna end the call here but you
get the idea and now this last one
Kember eScan is one of our marketing
folks he just returned from Antarctica
Ken's a great photographer and he took
all these great photos of of penguins in
Antarctica it's really cool this that's
great right in your email right on your
phone and if I want to by the way I can
look at my email with a split view just
like I do on my computer and so I can
select something here and just look at
it down here if I want to prove my
messages real fast and just find that
one message I was looking for but I
actually like the full screen view and
of course we have a standard inbox and
drafts and sent and you know in all
sorts of folders you can put things in
as well so it's real email just like
you're used to on your computer right
here on your phone it's extraordinary
and again free IMAP email from Yahoo now
let me go ahead and just create an email
message show you what that's like
so again when I don't need the keyboard
it's not there when I do it's there
want to send a message to let's say Phil
I just typed pH and boom Phil Schiller
its address completion and maybe I'll
send one to Scott Forstall as well and
there's Scott right there and let's say
the subject is dinner dinner and you
know oops see you tonight
boom and I just send send sends that
email and we're done
so that is mail full desktop class email
running on a mobile device alright now I
want to show you something incredible I
want to show you Safari running on a
mobile device so let's go to the web and
here we are I'm going to load in my
rather than Apple comm here a little
more Universal site I'm going to load in
the New York Times it's kind of a slow
site because it's got a lot of images
but here we are loading it we're loading
it over Wi-Fi right now and rather than
just give you a web version of the New
York Times rather than give you this
wrapped version all around we're showing
you the whole New York Times website and
there it is and guess what I can do I
can just put this into landscape mode
and there it is right there and I can
scroll here if I want scroll up and down
here boom still loading it in there we
go or I can just get back like this now
this is really great and I can see the
whole page but of course I can't read it
it's a little too small so I can get in
with my fingers and pinch it but we have
an optimization here I can just double
tap on anything and it automatically
fills up the screen with it and I can
just scroll around like this and scroll
over here and I can even make this text
bigger if I want to and there it is
and just double tap again to get back to
the full page isn't school and so I'm
just look at this there is the New York
Times and again any article I want boom
there we go boom unbelievable
now you can look at multiple web pages
as well you can have multiple web pages
open so I just push this button in the
lower right hand corner shrinks it down
and I could add a new page if I want and
I'll go to Amazon here out of my
bookmarks so let's go to Amazon and I
love to go to the DVD section of Amazon
and see what DVDs are selling I like it
especially when Disney's are at the top
and so here's a Amazon coming in even
before the whole page is loaded I'm just
gonna double tap on this and and I'm
gonna say let's go to the DVD section
here and now it's doing that
and here we are
and there's a section over here on the
right hand side right there and these
are the top sellers updated hourly oh
look Hal's An Inconvenient Truth is
number one all right and here's all the
other movies Grey's Anatomy I like that
Pirates of the Caribbean fantastic and
so I've got this right here and I can go
back to the New York Times if I want
yeah let's zoom up to that picture so we
can all see it and again here and that's
cool just over there go back to this one
I can get rid of them just by hitting
the X and there we go isn't that
incredible Safari
you know if you've ever used what's
called a web browser on a mobile phone
you'll know how incredible this is I
hope you never really know because it's
it's bad out there today and this is a
revolution of the first order to really
bring the real Internet to your phone
let me show you some about widgets here
let's go to stocks right now we're gonna
load stock information off the web and
just right onto the phone here oh look
apples up that's great I can look at the
graphs here if I want to and that's
fantastic let's look at the percentages
here oh good good good so I've got
stocks right here and I can go look at
the weather let's see what what it's
like outside 49 degrees but it's
supposed to get the 61 today so that's
good we'll just stay in here till it
warms up now I've got Paris right here I
can have as many of these as I want so
it's night time in Paris it's actually
warmer in Paris at night than it is here
today Wow Aspen yeah no snow till later
in the week and Hawaii oh it's raining
that's not good well anyway here's four
places Hawaii Aspen Paris and San
Francisco and again the weather widget
now to conclude with the internet device
section here I want to show you
something truly remarkable which is
Google Maps on iPhone I hit our Maps
application here and it's coming up and
it shows us North America and I'm gonna
go to Moscone West that's where we are
right now and here we are boom that's
where we are now what I'm gonna do is
I'm gonna go look for something I'm
gonna certainly want a cup of coffee
afterwards so I'm just gonna look for
Starbucks right Starbucks so I'm going
to search for Starbucks and sure enough
there's all the Starbucks
now I can get a list of Starbucks here
so I can pick that one if I want and I
can even go look at that Starbucks and
there it is
and let's give them a call good morning
yes I'd like to order 4,000 lattes to go
please no it's just kidding
wrong number thank you
I can zoom in by just again pinching if
I want to or I can just double click to
zoom in and I get just higher and higher
resolution versions of the map so let's
go somewhere else here that I've got
bookmarked and let's go to Washington
monuments and so here is Washington DC
and I could just double tap and and I'm
going in a little further here just
double tapping in and there's the
Washington Monument there and I'll
double tap in again and but now I want
to show you something else
satellite images so I just hit this
button called satellite down at the
bottom and it's going to replace the map
with satellite images there we go
and I can just double tap in and double
tap in again and let's catching up to me
here there we go and let's double tap in
again this is the Washington Monument
there we go look this you see people
down
yep
and that incredible right on my phone
it's unbelievable so let's go I've got
another one the Eiffel Tower which is
very cool I set this one not to be loose
there's the Eiffel Tower there's people
at the Eiffel Tower you can see look at
that incredible and here just one last
one I have to show you the Colosseum in
Rome so again here we are in Rome that's
as far as we can go with the map but we
can go a little further with the
satellite
there's the Colosseum there's the Roman
Colosseum satellite imagery right on the
phone look at that that's the Colosseum
unbelievable
so all these amazing things this is a
breakthrough internet communicator built
right into iphone the first rich HTML
email on a phone the first real web
browser on a phone best version of
Google Maps on the planet widgets and
all with edge and Wi-Fi networking we're
very very happy with this again email
push email IMAP free yahoo and almost
any other IMAP and POP mail service you
want to hook up to incredible new
technology for entering text far better
than we've seen on phones before a real
browser on the phone we can see real web
pages in portrait or landscape we can
zoom in on what we want to take a look
at more closely Google Maps and widgets
it's the Internet in your pockets for
the first time ever now
you can't you can't really think about
the Internet of course without thinking
about Google right and for Google what
we have on our phone working with them
is of course Google search we have that
built right into the browser just type
what you want hit Google and you're off
and Google Maps we've been working very
closely with them to make this all
happen
we're thrilled with the results and it's
my pleasure now to introduce dr. Eric
Schmidt Google's CEO
halation Steve what an incredible job so
Steve you know I've had the privilege of
joining joining the board and there's a
lot of relationships between the boards
and I thought you know if we just sort
of merge the companies we could call
them Apple goo but I'm not a marketing
guy what I like about this new device
and the new architecture of the Internet
is that you can actually merge without
merging Steve says that each company
should do the absolutely best thing that
they can do every time and I think he's
shown it once again today and internet
architectures right you know internet
architectures allow you now to take the
enormous brain trust that is represented
by the Apple development team and
combine that with the open protocols and
data services that companies like Google
and the others represented that are
coming up in in a bit to actually put
them together in a seamless environment
for end-users what I particularly like
about this is it's the first time it's
all to come together in one place now
from a Google perspective what we've
done is we've pushed very very hard to
partner with others in particular to
partner with Apple the companies the
cultures are similar innovation having
fun while you're doing it and also
working with many many different data
services so Steve showed a little bit of
some of the components some of the
pieces and so forth that you can do but
understand that this is a set of data
that's from maps and partners and so
forth so that you really can get the
full integration the person doesn't
understand how hard it was to get it all
together it comes together seamlessly
from my perspective this is the first of
a whole new generation of data services
where these powerful based cloud
computers Google being we hope a leading
representative provides HTML XML and
other sophisticated services that the
Safari browser that's embedded in the
iPhone and many other of its type
devices and future devices
Apple will be able to take advantage
Steve my congratulations to you and this
product is going to be hot
as a board member you'll get one of the
first ones yeah okay
now you also can't think about the
internet without thinking about Yahoo
and again on the phone we've got Yahoo
search built right in you can select
which one you want to use just type in
something hit that Yahoo button and boom
you're off and of course we also have
Yahoo IMAP email services and so it is
my great pleasure to introduce Jerry
Yang co-founder and chief Yahoo Jerry
thank you thank you thank you Steve I'm
not a board member of Apple but I would
love that one of these two obviously Wow
all this for a phone pretty incredible
and what a great device Steve we are
really proud at Yahoo to be partnering
with Apple on not only the Yahoo IMAP
email the first one we're doing but also
hopefully on a whole variety of other
popular services from Yahoo one of the
things that we're going to be doing with
Apple is also launching some of our new
services that we announced this week the
Yahoo go Yahoo
one search and hopefully we can get
Yahoo one search which is one of our new
products honor this phone which is a
really innovative way of looking at
search you're really able to not get the
traditional web search results but
rather get all the things you want in a
very concise format aggregated if you're
typing things like San Francisco you'll
get all the local news local weather and
local maps all in one place so we're
looking forward to doing that as Steve
said Mayo is a killer app on it on the
on the phone and Yahoo is really trying
to re design and re innovate and
reinvent the web experience and Internet
experience on the mobile devices so on
the email you can look forward not only
to great web services like the best spam
protection address books integration and
a calendar if you're on Yahoo just think
it's basically like having a blackberry
without the exchange server this is
really going to be really great not only
having a seamless experience from your
PC taken to your mobile internet yeah
there's some clapping out there I can
hear that lastly we want to be able to
really take what Apple is doing on the
phone by reinventing the phone and
reinventing the device we want to be
able to do that on the internet and what
we're doing is really being able to take
great form factors great user
experiences and great UI that we're
taking from not only the web but also in
the backend services and translate them
into a seamless web experience so we're
big believers and great hardware and
great software and we're big believers
in taking the web services and web 2.0
model and take it into the device world
so Steve my address you had it all
please send it to me
thanks again straight
thank you
you know it's been great having the two
greatest companies on the web right down
the block
Google and Yahoo and we've been able to
work with these guys really closely and
it's been an incredible pleasure to work
on this great technology and bring it to
everybody in iphone so thank you guys so
much you've really helped us put the
internet in your pocket so internet
communicator an iPod and a phone let's
put them all together and see what you
can do in a real life scenario so let's
take a look I'm I want listen to some
music so I'm gonna go into my iPod here
and let's see an artist's I want to
listen to oh maybe
Red Hot Chili Peppers I love those guys
and so I'm listening to a song of theirs
and let's see what happens when I get a
phone call music fades out screen
changes phone call coming in so I can
ignore it but I think I'm gonna answer
it so I'll answer it howdy hi Phil now
knows who Phil is because he's in my
address book so it puts his little
picture up here and everything up there
yeah how I feel listen I'm kind of busy
right now what I do for you okay hold on
just sec so I push the home button here
down at the bottom and I go home right
here and I'm still on the call you can
see the the phone thing flashing right
there on the lower left and I go into
photos and now I'm in photos and again
you can see the bar across the top the
green bar I can just touch that to
return to the call and Phil wants a
photo that he wanted to use it for a
screen saver it was one of the ones that
was taken in Hawaii I think it was this
one yep there it is so you want me to
mail this to you Phil all right so I
again I just go down here and push this
button and rather than use it as
wallpaper I'm gonna email it and so
watch what happens now it shrinks it a
little bit and then a compose window
will come up right behind it there we go
and I will just tap in the to field and
send this to Phil here Phil Schiller
there we go and the email is there yep
it's there and I'm just going to send it
hey Phil that should be on its way right
now okay yep anything else maybe catch a
movie tonight let me go check it out
I've got I think I got Fandango and my
bookmarks here and yes I do let's go to
Fandango figure out what movies are
playing
don't want to read too much into it
okay here's Fandango let's just
DoubleTap and here's the movies playing
yep how about we go see Night at the
Museum I haven't seen that yet great all
righty
hey take care of Phil now what I'm going
to do is to go back to my call I just
touch the top here and I'm back at my
call and I'm just going to go ahead and
end the call and what happens now back
in my music
so this is what it's like when you put
it all together
iPhone today Apple is reinventing the
phone now how does this stack up let's
go back to to these guys let's take a
look well these are their these are
their home screens and again as you
recall this is iPhones home screen this
this is what their contacts look like
this is what iPhones contacts look like
and again you just pick one and you see
everything about that person all the
information you have this is what mail
looks like on these smart phones again
this is what mail looks like on iPhone
you have rich HTML rich text email this
is what calendars look like on these
guys that's what calendars look like on
iPhone this is what the web looks like
and we tried to make it look as good as
we could on these it usually looks worse
and this is what you get and of course
this is what you get on iphone and you
can zoom in and see anything you want
and this is what you get from music
players nobody really uses a much and
this is what you get on iphone so after
today I don't think anyone's gonna look
at these phones quite the same way again
now let me tell you about some
accessories we've got for iPhone got
some great stereo headphones we're going
to be shipping and they've got a little
addition to them which is this little
thing right over here it's a microphone
and a switch so you can talk you have
them in there you can get a call just
talk the beautiful reception on the
microphone and just push it together to
answer a call or hang up on a call and
so you can be wearing them and just
dangles right there and picks up your
voice beautifully and we also have a
Bluetooth accessory headset that we're
going to be shipping and there it is
right there it's incredibly small and
just to let you see what it looks like
it's got one button on the top for
answering and hanging up a phone call
you never have to turn it off or on it
just goes to sleep
it
we pairs with iPhone so you don't have
to worry about pairing it's really
simple and it's very tiny this is what
it looks like in here it's just
beautiful it's the coolest one that
we've ever seen
so Bluetooth headset coming as well
battery life there's a lot of stuff a
lot of these phones a lot of these
smartphones have pretty pretty low
battery lights we've managed to get five
hours of battery and that's for talktime
or video or browsing five hours of
battery life and 16 hours of audio
playback so that's dramatically better
than any of these smart phones there's a
tremendous amount of high technology in
iphone we've been pushing the state of
the art in every facet of this design so
let me just talk a little bit about it
here we've got the multi-touch screen a
first miniaturization more than we've
ever done before a lot of custom silicon
tremendous power management OS 10 inside
a mobile device
featherweight precision enclosures 3
advanced sensors desktop class
applications and of course the
widescreen video iPod we've been
innovating like crazy for the last few
years on this and we filed for over 200
patents for all the inventions in iPhone
and we intend to protect
a lot of high technology I think we're
advancing the state-of-the-art in every
aspect of this design so iPhone is like
having your life in your pocket
it's the ultimate digital device so what
should we price it at
well what do these things normally cost
an iPod the most popular iPod $199 for 4
gig Nano what's a smartphone cost well
they they say you get the phone and some
of the internet with it although that's
questionable but they cost somewhere
between around $2.99 you can get them
for $1.99 pomme just introduced a new
one at 399 yesterday so it generally
averaged about $2.99 with a two-year
contract now these phones sort of do
music but nobody uses them for music cuz
they're not very good and so they end up
buying an iPod to go with the phone we
know we sell the iPod and so people
spend four hundred and ninety nine
dollars on this combination what should
we charge for iPhone because iPhones got
a lot more than this stuff right it's
got video real video it's got what this
beautiful gorgeous widescreen it's got
multi-touch user interface it's got
Wi-Fi it's got a real browser
it's got HTML email it's got Cover Flow
and on and on and on and this stuff
would normally cost hundreds of dollars
so how much more than $4.99 should we
price iPhone well we thought long and
hard about it because iPhone just does
so much stuff so much better experience
on a call and managing your contacts and
visual voicemail random access voicemail
for the first time and texting and email
and real browser and Google Maps and
tremendous iPod and Cover Flow and video
what should we price this thing at well
for for gigabyte model we're gonna price
it at that same $4.99 no premium
whatsoever for $99 and we're gonna have
an 8 gigabyte model for just $5.99 so if
you're gonna price it starting at 499
dollars now when's it going to be
available we're gonna be shipping these
in June yeah
June we're announcing it today because
with products like this we got to go and
get FCC approval which takes a few
months and we thought it'd be better if
we introduced this rather than asked the
FCC introduced to introduce it for us so
here we are we're gonna be shipping it
in June in the US we're going to Europe
hopefully by the 4th calendar quarter of
this year and Asia in 2008 so Jun in
just a few months we'll be shipping in
the US and when we do our partner is
going to be singular we've chosen
singular they are they are the best and
most popular network in the country 58
million subscribers they are number one
and they're going to be our exclusive
partner in the u.s. now it's a unique
partnership though we're not just going
to be selling phones and services
together we're going to be doing
innovation together we worked with
singular on visual voicemail because
it's an innovation that requires both
innovation on the phone and in the
network you can't do it in just one
place you have to do it in both places
and collaborate and so visual voicemail
is the first fruit of this collaboration
and you will see more and when we start
shipping in june will be selling iphone
through our own stores and through
singular stores and it's my pleasure to
introduce the CEO of singular stand
signal
congratulations my friend
thank you well the slipper thank you
thank you you know Steve and I first met
about two years ago in New York City
when he shared with me this vision that
he had for this product and we've been
working on it for some time and actually
entered into a contractual agreement
without us ever seeing the device or the
phone that was because of the confidence
that I have it's Steve and his
leadership team to deliver on the vision
that they have and every time I see this
it's just wow it's just wow it's really
really cool you've exceeded my
expectation
it's a real honor for singular to be
partnering with Apple today and I
brought with me another company to
celebrate in this and it's a pretty big
company it's the new AT&amp;T you know 11
days ago 18 T became a full part
I mean senior became a full part of the
new AT&amp;T family and this new family will
help fulfill the vision we have of
wireline wireless broadband and video
coming together on one device in the
ways that customers haven't imagined
today singular and Apple are truly
raising the bar we're announcing a
partnership that the mobile phone
experience takes in the mobile phone
experience to a real new level by
bringing together the best network with
the best device networks or the
foundation of what singular an AT&amp;T do
singular offers the largest digital and
voice data network in America today the
singular network has the fewest drop
calls in this country an AT&amp;T is the
largest provider of broadband internet
services in this community when it comes
to networks 80 wrote the book their
quality is legendary put this network
experience that singular and 80 have and
Apple products together and what do you
get first you get the best voice and
data services with the best user
experience available anywhere second you
get real compelling products and
services for example there's a voice
visual voicemail that Steve mentioned
which lets you look at the voice message
you want to hear and when you want to
hear it as Steve mentioned to create the
visual voicemail
it took innovation on singers part at
the network level and by Apple
with the device and I promise you'll see
more of that coming down the road
third when you bite combine singulars
2100 retail stores in number one
wireless online store with Apple's
already legendary retail stores and
online stores
you've got unmatched distribution yes
we're truly pleased to partner with
Apple to lit to deliver one of the most
eagerly awaited wireless products ever
the iPhone that he showed you with the
iPhone you get a breakthrough wireless
experience and we'll be working
shoulders shoulder with Steve and his
team to make sure that the integration
of the iPhone and our network is
seamless
this is only the beginning we are just
introducing a new product we're changing
the way companies work together Apple
and singular have a multi-year exclusive
partnership the new iPhone is only
available with singular wireless
services this is not an MVNO ours is a
unique relationship that lets Apple be
Apple that's singular be singular
Apple has built a device combining the
best phone iPod and mobile Internet
experience ever
iPhone owners will be singular and AT&amp;T
customers our customers will get the
best network and services in the
business people will benefit from the
best that companies they already know
and trust and what they have to offer
Apple singular and AT&amp;T have come a long
ways and now we're picking up the pace a
little over six years ago BellSouth and
80 came together to form singular 11
days singular joined the new 8
- today singing er and 80 are working
together to provide our customers the
most innovative enjoyable and reliable
service in the industry I hope you're as
excited as we are
that's what we have to see and enjoy
here this is going to be a terrific ride
thank you very much Steve
and congratulations
you know as Stan said we started working
together about two years ago and we come
from pretty different worlds the
telecommunications industry the computer
industry and of course music with the
iPod and and yet we have worked
wonderfully together and we love these
guys and we think it's we're gonna bring
some great stuff to market over the
years together so let's take a look at
at this market and how big it is
my clickers not working oh there it is
maybe it is working so how big is this
market well let's take a look
clicker is not working all right
there's scrambling backstage right now
you know when I was in high school Steve
Wozniak and I mostly Steve made this
little device called a TV jammer and it
was this it was this little oscillator
that put our frequencies that would
screw up the TV and was what have it in
this pocket and we go into like a dorm
at Berkeley where he was going to school
and a bunch of folks would be watching
like Star Trek and he screw up the TV
and somebody go up to fix it and and
just as they had their foot off the
ground he turned it back on if they put
their foot back on the ground he screw
up the TV again and within five minutes
he'd to have somebody like this for the
rest of the Star Trek episode okay so
maybe it's working now maybe they're
gonna have to click them for me so game
consoles 26 million game consoles were
sold in 2006 worldwide actually a little
smaller than you'd think
it's not such a big market digital
cameras dwarfed it at 94 million mp3
players 135 million and PCs about 209
mobile phones just about a billion last
year worldwide so what does this tell
you what this tells you is that one
percent market share equals 10 million
units this is a giant market if you just
one percent market share you're gonna
sell 10 million phones and this is
exactly what we're gonna try to do in
2008 our first full year in the market
is grab 1 percent market share and go
from there so we're gonna enter a very
competitive market a lot of players we
think we're gonna have the best product
in the world and we're gonna go for it
and see if we get one percent market
share 10 million units in 2008 and go
from there so today we've added to the
Mac and the iPod we've added Apple TV
and now iPhone and you know the Mac is
the only one that you really think of as
a computer right and so we thought about
this and we thought you know maybe our
name should reflect this a little bit
more than it
so we're announcing today we're dropping
the computer from our name and from this
day forward we're going to be known as
Apple incorporated to reflect the
product mix that we have today
you know I didn't sleep a wink last
night and I was so excited about today
because we've been so lucky at Apple
we've had some real revolutionary
products the Mac in 1984 is an
experience that those of us that were
there will never forget and I don't
think the world will forget it either
the iPod in 2001 changed everything
about music and we're gonna do it again
with the iPhone in 2007 we're very
excited about this you know there's an
old Wayne Gretzky quote that I love I
skate to where the puck is going to be
not where it has been and we've always
tried to do that at Apple since the very
very beginning and we always will so
thank you very very much